Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
I love you.
我爱你。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right.
好的。
Welcome back to the Ethereum Protocol Fellowship study group.
欢迎回到以太坊协议研究小组。
We are here on the seventh week, the development track today with Dragan from Reth, here to talk about the intricacies of an execution client.
我们在第七周，今天与Reth的Dragan一起开发轨道，在这里谈论执行客户的复杂性。
So, Mario, if you want to give a quick introduction for Dragan, and we will get started here.
因此，马里奥（Mario），如果您想对Dragan进行快速介绍，我们将在这里开始。
Yeah, of course. First of all, thank you so much Dragan for coming it's an honor to have you here
是的，当然。首先，非常感谢Dragan来到这里很荣幸
because you really fit in our study group schedule. We had Constance and Execution Layer Specs
因为您真的很适合我们的学习小组时间表。我们有康斯坦斯和执行层规格
last week in the first part of the development track and starting from the abstract level of
上周在开发轨道的第一部分，从抽象级别开始
Specs, we are now going to dive into the actual client this week, the Execution Client, and it's
规格，我们现在将在本周进入实际客户端，执行客户端，这是
it's really great to have Dragan representing Red here.
在这里有Dragan代表红色真的很棒。
Red is relatively new,
红色相对较新，
I believe it's the youngest execution client at this point.
我相信这是目前最年轻的执行客户。
Before, we had a similar dive from Matt into Get,
以前，我们从马特（Matt）进行了类似的潜水，
not that Get specific,
不是很具体，
but still Get is basically the oldest living client.
但是，仍然基本上是最古老的生活客户。
And today we will have the comparison,
今天我们将进行比较，
the big architectural changes that Red did,
雷德做的很大的建筑变化，
because Red is very interesting,
因为红色很有趣，所以
not just from the perspective of being new,
不仅从新的角度来看，
in Rust, but making many interesting choices and overhauling the whole execution layer design.
在生锈中，但是做出许多有趣的选择并大修整个执行层设计。
So it's very interesting to learn from you. Dragan is creator of RV-EVM, the Rust
因此，向您学习非常有趣。 Dragan是RV-EVM的创建者，Rust
implementation of the EVM, and I believe the lead developer of Red, correct me if I'm wrong there,
EVM的实施，我相信Red的首席开发人员，如果我错了，请纠正我，
but one of the main maintainers of the Red, which, by the way, recently became
但是红色的主要维护者之一，顺便说一句，最近变成了
uh Beta production ready uh mostly right uh so congrats on that it's it's really great and uh
嗯，beta生产准备好了，嗯，嗯
you're here to present it so yeah the stage is yours uh please uh feel free to share your screen
您在这里展示它，是的，舞台是您的嗯，请随时分享您的屏幕
and um and uh dive into the red code base uh hi hello everybody uh yeah I am before the revm and
嗯，uh潜入红色代码基础uh你好，大家好，是的，我是在revm之前
before that i was part of open ethereum and i worked on one of the rust client it got deprecated
在那之前，我是公开以太坊的一部分，我从事了一位生锈客户，它被弃用了
and after that revm got used by foundry and everything and judges came say hey let's build
在那之后，Revm被Foundry使用，所有内容和法官来了说嘿，让我们建造
a client and judges leading the main effort around it so i joined help a little bit and
客户和法官领导着围绕它的主要努力，所以我加入了一些帮助，
And yeah, I'm there and doing RET and REVM and everything, everything between.
是的，我在那里，做ret和revm以及一切之间的一切。
Let's start sharing screen.
让我们开始共享屏幕。
Yeah, a shameful screen.
是的，一个可耻的屏幕。
Sorry about this.
对此很抱歉。
Let's start for...
让我们开始...
Just a second.
仅一秒钟。
Yeah.
是的。
This is a quick presentation that Georgios did recently.
这是Georgios最近做的快速演讲。
It's a good-like introduction on the RET, how it started,
这是对RET的好介绍，它的开始方式，
basically where are we now and the future and hours that we want to make
基本上，我们现在在哪里，我们想要创造的未来和时间
and where we want to basically move it.
以及我们基本上要移动它的地方。
it's introduced in December 2020 it's it was in that point of time it was a few months of effort
它是在2020年12月推出的
I think we just finished our off-site where we finally appeared over P2P so that was very
我认为我们刚刚完成了我们终于在P2P上出现的现场，所以非常
exciting at that point of time we only had like evm that's uh used it foundry and it was very
在那个时间点令人兴奋
exciting times uh first release of happened in June uh basically this is where we synced the
激动人心的时代UH首次发行了6月的第一次发行，这是我们同步的地方
client where we successfully synced from Genesis to the tip of the chain and yeah that's where we
我们从创世纪成功同步到链的尖端的客户，是的，这就是我们
entered alpha software.
输入Alpha软件。
And just recently, like few weeks ago,
就像几周前一样，最近
we entered beta.
我们进入了Beta。
Few of our requirement for entering beta
我们输入beta的要求很少
was some breaking changes on database that we had.
是我们所拥有的数据库的一些破坏变化。
And we started auditing both the RET and our EVM
我们开始审核RET和EVM
so that we are more sure
这样我们就更确定
that the client behaves as it should be.
客户的行为应应有的。
It helps a lot when you have audits done.
进行审核后，它很有帮助。
But even without that, there is a big user base
但是即使没有，也有一个大的用户群
that all the user at in production,
所有用户都在生产中，
and it was very nice to see that.
很高兴看到这一点。
If I read, those are few points, client diversity,
如果我读到，那是几点，客户多样性，
Having fast, stable client that everybody can use for staking or just tinkering around it,
拥有快速，稳定的客户，每个人都可以用来堆放或在周围修补它，
or just using it for some hobby projects, or even using it for production to facilitate any provider infrastructure that they need.
或仅将其用于某些爱好项目，甚至将其用于生产来促进所需的任何提供商基础架构。
Talent resilience, more people knowing about core dev, knowing about core protocol.
人才弹性，更多的人了解核心开发人员，了解核心协议。
That's all it goes to see.
这就是一切。
clients stability uh yeah we need client to build the high gas per second l2 world we want to extend
客户稳定性呃，是的，我们需要客户来建立我们想要扩展的每秒L2世界的高气
red to be uh to be usable by a lot of people even l2 cell trees whatever they come and codex stability
红色uh可以被很多人使用
it should be easy to extend rpc to extend evm with new pretty copals average around it
延长RPC应该很容易扩展EVM，而围绕它的新漂亮的代码
Fastest goals, L1 Ethereum usage, fastest L2, and infrastructure for building EVM.
最快的目标，L1以太坊的使用，最快的L2和用于构建EVM的基础设施。
We are very open for any contributor that wants to basically jump into the code or check
对于任何想基本上跳入代码或检查的贡献者，我们都很开放
for good first issues and just open pr we're very proud for that because they have good
对于一个好的第一个问题，只需打开公关，我们就为此感到自豪，因为它们有好处
fast first response for any core contributors and that's why we have these nice stats
任何核心贡献者的快速回应，这就是为什么我们拥有这些不错的统计数据
they are basically growing we are growing the stars stars and unique contributors
他们基本上正在成长，我们正在发展星星和独特的贡献者
uh we are fast uh for syncing red from the Genesis to the tip it takes 50 hours and it
嗯，我们很快就可以将红色从创世纪同步到尖端，需要50个小时
is around two gigabytes two terabytes of data
大约是两个gigabytes数据
uh historical sync breakdown ah this was for 2023 uh we just recently with the beta switch
嗯，历史同步崩溃啊，这是2023年，我们刚刚使用Beta Switch
to the static files i'll talk about that a little bit later but our archive node is
对于静态文件，我将稍后再讨论，但我们的存档节点是
around two terabytes while our full node is around one terabyte a single time in 2024 is 48
大约两个terabytes虽然我们的完整节点在2024年一次大约是一口
while in 2023 it was 50. so even with increased
虽然在2023年是50。
state and increased like new blocks came for a year we are now a little bit faster than
状态和像新街区一样增加了一年，我们现在比
we were a year ago but we'll know this even more uh because we don't save all the data
我们是一年前，但我们会更了解这一点，因为我们没有保存所有数据
So 42 hours for full genesis to the tip sync is very nice.
因此，全身为尖端同步的42小时非常好。
There is the Ergon and what we used from it.
有埃尔贡（Ergon）和我们从中使用的东西。
We have split how we sync the blocks.
我们已经分割了如何同步块。
We have historical sync.
我们有历史同步。
Basically, the part of the rat is optimized to sync historical blocks.
基本上，大鼠的一部分被优化为同步历史块。
and we can see that we can have two or depending on the block this is millions of blocks we can
我们可以看到，我们可以有两个或取决于块，这是我们可以的数百万块
have two giga gas per second for historical sync because we optimize on that and while on the live
每秒有两个GIGA气体用于历史同步，因为我们对此进行了优化
sync where we include block by block and check the state routes for every block it is a lot less
同步我们在其中包含块，并检查每个块的状态路线少得多
it's 100 to 200 megabytes per second mega gas per second this is measured by mega it labs
每秒是每秒100兆字节的100兆字节
we benchmark those stuff by flood and by creo but very nice tools made by paradigm
我们通过洪水和克雷奥（Creo）对这些东西进行基准测试，但范式制造的非常好
yeah we are currently transitioning we transition to the beta and we have support for the cancun and
是的，我们目前正在过渡到过渡到Beta，我们对坎昆和
and everything like that.
以及这样的一切。
We are fuzzing the EVM currently, and we support OP stack.
我们目前正在弄大EVM，我们支持OP堆栈。
Snapshot syncs are done by the Merkle.
快照同步由Merkle完成。
You don't even need to sync from JS to the tip.
您甚至不需要从JS到小费同步。
You can just download the snapshot and just reuse it.
您只需下载快照即可重复使用。
We have good docs that are nice to read.
我们有一个很好的文档可以阅读。
based on RPC with all the traces that you need.
基于RPC，带有所需的所有迹线。
Yeah, we get RET in recently just entered protocol guild.
是的，我们获得了最近刚进入协议公会的RET。
That was very nice to see.
很高兴看到。
In production, this one meme that was made,
在生产中，这是一个模因
I'm running Validato with RET Prism, run test net, right?
我正在使用Ret Prism，运行测试网的有效托托，对吗？
Test net.
测试网。
So there are people running RET.
因此，有人在跑步。
And even as the validator, it's very nice to see.
即使作为验证者，也很高兴看到。
We target production to be production-ready in May.
我们以生产为目标，将于5月准备生产。
So there are two audits currently in progress.
因此，目前正在进行两项审核。
SimulPrior does the RET, and REVM is done by Gaudo.
SimulPrior进行了RET，REVM由Gaudo完成。
He's first ETH bug bounty leader on leaderboard.
他是排行榜上的第一位ETH Bug Bounty领导者。
And there is cheat tracks for development performance.
并且有发展绩效的作弊曲目。
So there's few paths that we can be exploring
因此，我们可以探索的路径很少
from gTVM to Parallel-EVM
从GTVM到平行evm
to be just paralyzed our market tree calculation
只是瘫痪了我们的市场树计算
that's currently merged.
目前已合并。
And kernel is allowing modification
内核允许修改
modification on the current code outside of the repo.
在存储库之外的当前代码进行修改。
So you don't need to clone it.
因此，您无需克隆它。
You need to fork it and make changes.
您需要分叉并进行更改。
That can be very troublesome and time-consuming.
这可能非常麻烦且耗时。
You can just use all but all these there and just extend it
您只能在那里使用所有这些，但可以扩展它
by RPC endpoint or Nuprix Opal.
由RPC端点或Nuprix Opal。
We shipped Cancun via on top of the Electro Prague.
我们通过电布格的顶部运送了Cancun。
I'm basically working on EOF currently.
我基本上是从事EOF的工作。
We are looking in vertical trees, account obstruction.
我们正在垂直树，帐户障碍物。
There are few APIs implemented as the part of the kernel,
作为内核的一部分，很少有API，
or part of the node builder, sorry.
或部分节点构建器的一部分，对不起。
Yeah, performance, this is paths that we investigate currently.
是的，性能，这是我们目前研究的途径。
Some of them are probably going to be implemented.
其中一些可能将被实施。
All right, kernel is SDK for bleeding-edge EVM infrastructure.
好吧，内核是用于出血边缘EVM基础架构的SDK。
Basically, you can make pluggable components that plug in the current node
基本上，您可以制作可插拔的组件来插入当前节点
and just extend it.
并扩展它。
A few ideas to merge a lot of project that needs to be run in the parallel
一些想法要合并很多项目，这些项目需要在平行的情况下运行
into one binary that can be very nicely run mainnet
变成一个可以很好地运行主网的二进制
and everything is there.
一切都在那里。
These are a few examples.
这些是一些例子。
I will go over them slightly.
我会稍微浏览它们。
This is examples of RedKernel.
这是Redkernel的示例。
And beyond, yeah, multi-node roll-ups, multi-tenants, node architecture.
是的，是的，多节点卷，多租户，节点体系结构。
Sure, we'll see it will be very nice to have like breath node mainnet, top mainnet, everything
当然，我们会看到拥有呼吸节点的主网，顶部的mainnet，一切都会非常好
running on with one command, but this is more like mid to not immediate priority, not immediate.
用一个命令继续进行，但这更像是中间，而不是直接的优先级，而不是直接的。
Yeah.
是的。
I'm sure if you guys have any comments or anything you want to ask or anything you want
我敢肯定，你们是否有任何评论或任何您想问的东西或您想要的任何东西
to say, just write it and I will see it to answer it.
要说，只需写它，我会看到它回答。
I will check chat from time to time.
我会不时检查聊天。
Mario, if you can ping me from-
马里奥，如果你能从
Yeah, most of the time our chat happens in a Discord channel, which I can send you
是的，大多数时候我们的聊天发生在不和谐频道中，我可以向您发送
a link to if you want to join it.
如果您想加入它的链接。
But Mario and I will triage most of the questions that happen in that channel and answer what we can,
但是马里奥和我将分类大多数在该渠道中发生的问题，并回答我们能做的事情，
and then bring up any questions that seem relevant or pertinent for you to answer.
然后提出任何似乎相关或相关的问题。
Okay, nice.
好吧，很好。
That sounds great.
听起来很棒。
Great.
伟大的。
Yeah, I want to do a quick introduction.
是的，我想快速介绍。
These slides were very great about that.
这些幻灯片非常好。
So after that, I know that this is expected to be more technical, so I will dive into the code.
因此，在那之后，我知道这将是更具技术性的，因此我将研究代码。
and check components that are interested, that is different from the get architecture
并检查感兴趣的组件，与GET架构不同
and why they are different and what the more differences that we have.
以及为什么它们与众不同以及我们有什么区别。
So, yeah, hope that it's okay.
所以，是的，希望没关系。
Not RAM, but Paradym.
不是公羊，而是天堂。
Redd has a lot, Paradigm in general, it has a lot of projects that we work on.
雷德（Redd）有很多东西，总体而言，它有很多我们从事的项目。
Redd is the client that we work on.
Redd是我们从事的客户。
Foundry is testing for the testing and everything around it.
Foundry正在测试测试及其周围的所有内容。
Alloy is, it's mostly on the Redd dependencies.
合金是，它主要是在REDD依赖性上。
Alloy allows, it gives us the primitives, big numbers, it gives us RPC types, it gives
合金允许的，它为我们提供了原始数字，大数字，它为我们提供了RPC类型，它提供了
us everything around the, like, array coding, everything around it.
我们周围的一切，例如阵列编码，周围的所有内容。
So primitives are mostly found in the alloy.
因此，原始素大多在合金中找到。
There is REVM, it's just EVM that have journaling, it has, it allows running the section, whatever
有REVM，只是EVM具有日记，它允许运行该部分，无论如何
intersection that is and our rat is the the guy that used all that
交叉路口是，我们的老鼠是使用所有这些的人
and the main the client and binary project is divided in the binaries and the crates
客户和二进制项目的主要项目分为二进制文件和板条箱
binaries have just uh commands and basically encapsulating everything from the crates inside
二进制文件只有uh命令，基本上封装了内部板条箱的所有内容
it one crate.
它是一个板条箱。
And inside, there is a lot of crates that basically, we
在里面，基本上有很多板条箱
wanted to make it to be easy navigatable,
想让它变得容易导航，
and for every crate to be reusable by other parties.
并且每个板条箱都可以由其他各方重复使用。
For example, everything around storage is in the Site Storage,
例如，存储周围的所有内容都在网站存储中，
and we have database provider, codecs, everything
我们有数据库提供商，编解码器，所有内容
that encapsulates saving or loading data from the database.
这封装了从数据库中保存或加载数据。
This allows you use cases where you can use providers
这允许您使用可以使用提供商的情况
that are obstruction over the database,
在数据库上的阻塞，
that have some utility function, get block for example,
具有一定的实用程序功能，例如获取块，
and run that as the, use just this library
并以此为单位，仅使用此库
and run that as the standalone process that
并将其作为独立过程
can read directly for the database.
可以直接阅读数据库。
This is a very nice use case, because it gives you
这是一个非常好的用例，因为它给了您
a lot more performant reads.
表现更多的读物。
You don't need to ping JSON-RPC or IPC or everything like that.
您无需ping json-rpc或ipc或类似的一切。
You can directly read from the database, from the disk.
您可以直接从数据库中读取磁盘。
it was yeah maybe it's better to start um I think this this slides I made last year
是的，也许最好开始我，我认为这是我去年制作的幻灯片
but the few things have changed but um the main overlook is still the same
但是几件事发生了变化，但是嗯，主要忽略仍然相同
uh the red is driven by the engine engine is the main brain behind the
呃，红色由发动机驱动是
that drives every other component and it receives for choice update from the consensus layer
驱动所有其他组件，并从共识层获得选择更新
and checks if that block or hash that is received
并检查收到的那个块或哈希
for the consensus layer is valid
对于共识层有效
or basically decides what to do with it.
或基本上决定该怎么做。
There is, as I said, RAT has two modes of the syncing.
正如我所说，老鼠有两种同步模式。
One is the historical sync that's done by the pipeline.
一个是管道完成的历史同步。
Basically, pipeline executes, basically, syncs in the stages.
基本上，管道在阶段基本上执行同步。
and when you sync in the stages it you can optimize those stages and allow allows that
当您在阶段同步时，您可以优化这些阶段，并允许
allows you to be more optimized in basically faster and while when we are close to the tip
允许您在基本上更快地进行优化，而当我们靠近尖端时
of the of the chain we switch to the blockchain tree blockchain tree is another way that we sync
我们切换到区块链树区块链树的链条是我们同步的另一种方式
to basically near the tip where state truth, validation, execution happen everything inside
基本上是在状态真理，验证，执行发生的尖端附近
the memory only when the block gets canonicalized it get basically moved to the database provider
仅当块获得规范化时，内存基本上移动到数据库提供商
is abstraction over the database that allows some helper function so that we don't need to
是在数据库上抽象的，该数据库允许某些辅助功能，因此我们不需要
had to directly use key validation. Downloader it's used by both the pipeline for its first two stages
必须直接使用关键验证。下载器，这两个管道都在其前两个阶段使用
or by the engine if it needs to close the gap to the tip it's used to download blocks and headers
或通过引擎缩小差距到小费的差距，用于下载块和标题
from the p2p and it's basically from p2p we when we are close to the tip we push those new
从P2P，基本上是从P2P来
transactions that we receive to the section pool and the section pool basically it is ethereum's
我们收到的交易到部分池和部分池，基本上是以太坊的
ddos protection it has n number of the section ordered by uh the the gas price that users want
DDOS保护它具有用户想要的汽油价格订购的部分的n个数量
to pay and payload builder basically takes and first the sections build the new payload that's
付款和有效载荷构建器基本上采取并首先要构建新的有效载荷
needed for the engine a few more components are added uh like snapshotting snapshotting is
引擎所需的更多组件添加了uh，例如快照快照是
is our way how um just static file sorry static files where we move some data directly to the
我们的方式是um um只是静态文件对不起的静态文件，我们将一些数据直接移动到
different kind of database that that is in the binary form and the additional component is here
以二进制形式和附加组件的不同类型的数据库在这里
it's pruner it allows it allows us to have a full load basically after the blockchain tree
它是修剪器，它允许我们在区块链树之后基本上承担全部负载
canonicalize the block that block needs to wait for like additional two blocks 64 blocks to get
规范化块需要等待的块，就像其他两个块64个块获得
finalized after it gets finalized or i think we have some buffer 10k but after it gets finalized
最终确定后最终确定，或者我认为我们有一些缓冲区10K，但是在完成后完成
We know that it's not going to be reorg or if we are in the full node, we can remove some data.
我们知道它不会是reorg，或者如果我们在整个节点中，我们可以删除一些数据。
But yeah, those components are missing, but this flow is still the same or similar that it was before.
但是，是的，这些组件缺少，但是这种流程仍然与以前相同或相似。
Let's jump into, yeah, I think the main difference here is the in-pipeline, I will go over it.
是的，我认为这里的主要区别是围栏，我将仔细研究它。
Because the stages, how we download blocks, how we check the blocks are what's different
因为阶段，我们如何下载块，我们如何检查块是什么不同
from the get architecture.
从获得架构。
And I will go for that inside the code.
我将在代码中选择这一点。
Not that, RET.
不是那样，ret。
Creates RPC pipeline stages.
创建RPC管道阶段。
yes yeah but before that we take good care of adding a lot of documentation
是的，但是在此之前，我们会很好地添加大量文档
around mostly in the code so it's easier to modify and extend
大部分在代码中，因此更容易修改和扩展
so it would be good to check documentation first uh not that
因此，最好先检查文档是很好的
But it's pipeline, no, it's stages.
但这是管道，不，这是阶段。
Yeah.
是的。
Stage, in general, is very simple.
通常，舞台非常简单。
it have it's id it have execute like hey i need to execute you're the next for execution
它具有它的ID，就像嘿，我需要执行执行
unbind unbind is needed if some uh real happen and we need to unbind the
如果某些uh真实发生，则需要打开绑架，我们需要解开
that stage that basically can have side block or side data
基本上可以具有侧块或侧面数据的阶段
and this is helper function to fetch it if it is over ready or not
这是辅助功能是否准备就绪是否已准备就绪
Where is it?
它在哪里？
The stages.
阶段。
Pipeline.
管道。
Just a second.
仅一秒钟。
Okay, let's jump into the code.
好的，让我们跳入代码。
Maybe it's here.
也许在这里。
The pipeline basically consists of multiple stages.
管道基本上由多个阶段组成。
The pipeline is used for some of the command line interface to basically, if you want to
如果您想，该管道用于一些命令行接口
unwind just particular stage or we want to execute just particular stage it's used for
放松特定阶段，或者我们只想执行它用于的特定阶段
testing or use it for debugging or development or anything where you just want to, for example,
测试或使用它进行调试或开发或任何您只想的地方
run just Merkle stage, drop Merkle stage, drop those tables and just run it again.
刚开始默克尔舞台，放下默克尔舞台，放下那些桌子，然后再次运行。
Here's a list of default setup where we have from the first to the last stage.
这是我们从第一个到最后阶段的默认设置列表。
stage. First two stages, header stage and body stage are basically network stages where
阶段。前两个阶段，标题阶段和车身阶段基本上是网络阶段
they fetch in this stage headers and here they fetch bodies. They fetch it by the bundle
他们在这个阶段的标题中获取，在这里拿起身体。他们用捆绑包获取
of the end bodies and they need to wait for the p2p to for nodes that that we requested
末端的身体，他们需要等待P2P才能获得我们要求的节点
blocks to return the body or the header stage so that we need to take care if the body
块以返回身体或标头阶段，以便我们需要注意
or is not received or we need to check if that's correct body that we see
或未收到或我们需要检查我们看到的正确的身体是否正确
we cannot see the stages you're showing a different slide
我们看不到您正在显示不同幻灯片的阶段
Oh, I wanted to jump into the code.
哦，我想跳入代码。
Sorry.
对不起。
Yeah, we see different browser window.
是的，我们看到了不同的浏览器窗口。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Okay.
好的。
I didn't know that.
我不知道。
Let me stop sharing.
让我停止分享。
Sorry, I jumped into share screen.
抱歉，我跳入共享屏幕。
uh yeah i want to check this
是的，我想检查一下
uh can you see my
呃，你能看到我的
no we didn't see now
不，我们现在没看到
entire screen
整个屏幕
Okay, I need to enable it.
好吧，我需要启用它。
I need to come back.
我需要回来。
I need to reopen the Chrome.
我需要重新打开镀铬。
Just a second.
仅一秒钟。
Okay, so we have a quick intermission.
好的，所以我们有一个快速的中场休息。
Folks, meanwhile, feel free to ask any questions you had so far.
同时，人们可以随时提出到目前为止您遇到的任何问题。
And it's written in different.
它是不同的。
Mario, maybe you want to talk a little bit
马里奥，也许你想说一点
about what the difference is between a historical sync
关于历史同步之间的区别
and a live sync or a Snap sync sort of situation.
以及现场同步或SNAP同步情况。
Yeah, I wanted to ask Dragan so he can give more detailed
是的，我想问Dragan，以便他可以提供更多详细的信息
explanation, because it might be more specific to the red code
说明，因为它可能更特定于红色代码
base in generally.
一般而言。
it mean, like, whether the full node is pulling the current data and using them to sync or
它的意思是，是否全节点是在删除当前数据并使用它们同步或
seeing it from genesis?
从创世纪看到它？
There was some question about the live sync versus the historical sync, Dragan, but we
关于现场同步与历史同步，有些疑问，Dragan，但我们
can get into that later.
稍后可以进入。
Yeah.
是的。
Do you want it to go?
你要它去吗？
Yeah, it should be fine now.
是的，现在应该很好。
Just a second.
仅一秒钟。
I want to share my full screen and I jumped into VCCode.
我想分享我的全屏幕，然后跳入VCCODE。
Yeah.
是的。
Do you see it now?
你现在看到了吗？
Yes, perfect.
是的，完美。
Okay.
好的。
Sorry about that.
对此很抱歉。
I thought we had same.
我以为我们也有。
No problem.
没问题。
Yeah.
是的。
Do you want maybe to go over the questions or do you want to go over them later?
您是否想讨论问题，还是想以后再讨论？
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
We can cover some of the questions now.
我们现在可以解决一些问题。
So yeah, the question was, let me read it properly.
是的，问题是，让我正确阅读。
What is the difference between historical sync and a live sync?
历史同步和现场同步有什么区别？
P historical sync is like syncing historical blocks.
P历史同步就像同步历史块。
But live sync is syncing the blocks that come from the consensus layer.
但是实时同步正在同步共识层的块。
Those are the next block that's going to be proposed by consensus layer.
这些是下一个将由共识层提出的块。
While historical sync is syncing those blocks that are already proposed,
虽然历史同步正在同步已经提出的那些块，但
all the known, and all the verified.
所有已知的和所有已验证的。
So we have different kind of like assumptions here.
因此，我们在这里有不同类型的假设。
For consensus layer, when we receive block for consensus layer,
对于共识层，当我们收到共识层的块时，
which we receive just one block, maybe multiple blocks,
我们只收到一个街区，也许是多个块，
but they are mostly like near the tip, like the newest block.
但是它们大多就像在尖端附近，就像最新的块一样。
block but for the historical sync we have we all didn't know and we already know what block needs
块，但是对于历史同步，我们都不知道，我们已经知道哪些块需要
to be re-execute so we are executing everything again and we are executing them from like Genesis
要重新执行
to the the tip or the closed tip depending on what we what tip do we have yes so it's uh getting the
根据我们有什么尖端，我们有什么尖端或封闭的尖端
choice data from consensus layer versus like fetching the execution historical data and
从共识层的选择数据与获取执行历史数据和
so yeah what the red does it's like the stage sync uh the different different approach the historical
是的，红色的作用就像舞台同步uh不同的不同方法历史
scene which is highly optimized and that's what you were getting into just not showing yes uh so
高度优化的场景，这就是您所进入的目的，只是不显示是的
just so you guys have the context uh this is the one of the biggest differences the red uh
让你们有上下文，这是红色uh的最大区别之一
red architecture that it's using this stage sync and it's very interesting it's it's a different
它使用此阶段同步的红色架构非常有趣，这是一个不同的
different uh than that woodkit has um yeah and there was a there was a question exactly about
嗯，woodkit有不同的um，还有一个问题
this how is it different from arragon and aquila and this is stage sync it's something it was
这与Arragon和Aquila有何不同，这是舞台同步
pioneered by arragon so like if you can maybe summarize what are the other differences to to red
由Arragon开创的，因此，如果您可以总结红色的其他区别
uh difference from the arragon and aquila and
UH与Arragon和Aquila的差异以及
Basically, what we introduced recently are the static files.
基本上，我们最近介绍的是静态文件。
We are using our database, key value database, that here, like, B3 inside, basically, on
我们正在使用我们的数据库，密钥值数据库，例如，B3内部，基本上是在
the hard disk.
硬盘。
We just use it, just binary files.
我们只是使用它，只是二进制文件。
We put transactions, block, receipts, basically immutable data that we know it's not going
我们放置了交易，块，收据，基本上是我们知道的数据
be changed we put it in our format in the binary files and with that we got like a lot more database
要更改，我们将其以二进制文件的格式列出，并且我们得到了更多数据库
and even faster sync time for example yeah it's interesting yeah other than that
甚至更快的同步时间，例如是的
uh block uh sync it to tip with the blockchain trees everything is in the memory so we don't
uh块uh uh将其同步以与区块链树尖端，一切都在内存中，所以我们不
we don't have it in temporary files and all that so uh
我们没有临时文件，所以
that allows us to not store junk inside the database and
这使我们不得将垃圾存储在数据库中，并且
basically handle everything inside the memory and that handling is just depending data that's
基本上处理内存中的所有内容，而处理只是依赖于数据
still not verified so that's one of the differences uh cool it's very interesting
仍然没有验证，所以这是很酷的区别之一，这很有趣
because yeah uh i thought it first that it's going to have very similar but like i understand
因为是的，我首先认为它会非常相似，但就像我了解
the performance uh like go with some legacy get base versus rest will be faster but i was
表演uh，例如与一些遗产获得基础，而休息会更快，但我当时
surprised when i think that it was actually smaller at the time it looked healthy it's
当我认为当时它看起来很健康时，它很惊讶
more now it's maybe even more than uh than uh the everyone database it's uh yeah we did a lot
现在，它可能比每个人的数据库还要多，是的，我们做了很多
optimizations like uh comp uh basically compressing the data we have a custom encoding that encodes
诸如uh comp uh之类的优化基本上压缩了我们具有编码的自定义编码的数据
everything and even few for the for example any data and receive data we can use some compression
例如，所有数据和接收数据的一切，甚至很少，我们可以使用一些压缩
so that it's like shrink a lot uh yeah the main difference between while while this is even
这样就像缩水了很多，是的，而当时甚至是
possible is while the pipeline sync stage sync is valid is we don't do merkle verification on
可能是当管道同步阶段同步有效时，我们不对
every block while the other past client get open ethereum everything like passing generation did it
每个街区，而另一个过去的客户获得了公开的以太坊，就像传递一代一样做到了
at every block we do it only at the end so we still verify that our state is valid and everything
在每个块中，我们仅在最后才能做到这一点，因此我们仍然验证我们的状态是否有效，一切
state root is basically there but we don't have that overhead to check into every block
状态根基本上是在那里，但我们没有开销来检查每个块
right yeah that's it's a lot of nice computation there uh yeah interesting so we are getting back
是的，那是很多不错的计算，是的，很有趣，所以我们回来了
to the stage sync now and maybe so go ahead your screen and we can continue with that and then
现在到舞台同步，也许可以继续您的屏幕，我们可以继续进行此操作，然后继续
share screen
共享屏幕
Ah, here it is.
啊，在这里。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Yeah, we're a big fan of the docs.
是的，我们是文档的忠实拥护者。
So yeah, the pipeline has the default set of the stages, and those are used for initial
是的，管道具有阶段的默认集，它们用于初始阶段
sync, basically, when the pipeline is running inside the rep.
基本上，当管道在代表内部运行时，同步。
Few, this header stage and body stage are two stages that are separately.
很少有这个标题阶段和身体阶段是分别分别的两个阶段。
We first run headers, check the hashes, check basically the parent hash, if those match or not.
我们首先运行标头，检查哈希，基本上检查父母哈希，是否匹配。
After that, we basically download from P2P, a little bit heavier bodies.
之后，我们基本上是从P2P下载的，这有点重一些。
We do sender recovery stage. Sender recovery can be expensive, so we do it here for every
我们做发件人恢复阶段。发件人恢复可能很昂贵，所以我们在这里为每个
transaction that we receive in body stage we need to extract basically it's who sent it
我们在身体阶段收到的交易基本上需要提取它是谁发送的
at that our biggest stage is our most time consuming stage execution stage
在那我们最大的阶段是我们最耗时的舞台执行阶段
here we do basically take the sender transaction and header and just execute it inside the revm
在这里，我们确实将发件人交易和标题进行操作，然后在REVM中执行它
them. Output of this is basically we check if the gas is same. We basically create receipts
他们。输出基本上是我们检查气体是否相同。我们基本上创建收据
and we create the change sets. Change sets are the changes that happen between accounts
我们创建更改集。更改集是帐户之间发生的更改
in one block, so it's block-level change sets.
在一个块中，它是块级别的更改集。
If the executive block have three, four,
如果执行区有三个，四个，
two section, 100 section, we will take all those changes
两个部分，100部分，我们将进行所有这些更改
and make one hash map of that.
并制作一张哈希地图。
After that, in the execution flow,
之后，在执行流中，
this Merkle stage is skipped
这个默克尔阶段被跳过
because it has its own use when it's unwinding.
因为它在放松时就有自己的用途。
basically execution happens when you go from the top to the bottom,
基本上执行时，当您从顶部到底部时，
but unwind happens in different order, from the place where you want to unwind,
但是，放松的时间以不同的顺序发生，从您想放松的地方，
where you find some problems, to the top.
在哪里发现一些问题，到顶部。
Account hashing, account stage, basically in execution stage,
帐户哈希，帐户阶段，基本上处于执行阶段，
we have just the plain state where key value for the plain state is just address and the
我们只有一个普通的状态，即普通状态的关键价值仅为地址
account information that's balance notes and balance notes and code hash while berkeley needs
余额注释和余额笔记和代码哈希的帐户信息，而伯克利需要
that hashed and while it needs that hash it it matters because of the order so we have
哈希，虽然需要哈希，但由于订单，它很重要，所以我们有
I will go to database next and show you what exactly that means, how it's, how the database
我将下一步访问数据库，并向您展示这是什么意思，它的方式，数据库的方式
layout is, is made, but we need to take the plain state and hash it and save it in the
布局是制造的，但是我们需要采取平原状态并将其保存在
account, hashed account table.
帐户，哈希帐户表。
We do that same for the storage and then we do Merkle stage.
我们在存储中也这样做，然后进行默克尔阶段。
Merkle stage takes account, the storage, hashed account storages and creates basically state
默克尔阶段考虑了，存储，哈希帐户存储，并基本上说明
root and verify that state root is correct for the block that we need.
root并验证状态根对我们需要的块是正确的。
After that, we have, this is helper stage it allows us to do transaction lookup.
在那之后，我们拥有这是帮助我们进行交易查找的辅助阶段。
After that, those two stages allows us to access any history data.
之后，这两个阶段使我们能够访问任何历史记录数据。
Basically, execution stage created the change sets.
基本上，执行阶段创建了更改集。
Basically the data that was previously there before the block get executed.
基本上，在执行块之前先前的数据。
While those two stages index those.
而这两个阶段则索引。
thing is done so that it allows us for every block number that we want to get the account
这样做是为了使我们可以为我们要获得帐户的每个块号
balance for example or account nodes this uh yeah this allows us that ability same for
例如，平衡或帐户节点这个嗯，是的，这使我们能够相同的能力
The same for the storage.
对于存储而言，也是如此。
Sorry.
对不起。
Just back.
就回来了。
Same for the storage.
对于存储而言相同。
Similar thing is for account.
类似的是帐户。
And finished it, we just announce our end.
并完成了，我们只是宣布我们的结局。
That engine can start getting new consensus layer from
该引擎可以开始从中获得新的共识层
functions update from consensus layer.
功能从共识层进行更新。
If we go inside execution stage, it's not there.
如果我们进入执行阶段，那就不存在。
Let's go this.
让我们去。
stage is the biggest one so maybe it's better to go to send a recovery
舞台是最大的一个，所以最好去发送恢复
send a recovery it has like some commit threshold idea how you want to optimize this is you
发送一个恢复，就像某个提交阈值的想法您要如何优化这一点是您
want to have some bounds how much data are we going to to commit how much basically ram
想要有一些界限，我们将要提交多少基本上的数据
you want to have. I think this is just amount of the transaction you want to commit.
你想拥有。我认为这只是您要进行的交易的数量。
And for example, we check for execution in the send recovery.
例如，我们在发送恢复中检查执行。
We check, we get the input that says, hey, we want to execute this stage from the block
我们检查，我们得到的输入说，嘿，我们想从街区执行此阶段
block million to the block two million or million and a half uh we take the next block
盖百万到街区200万或一百万，一半uh我们取下下一个街区
range intersection basically we take blocks in that range it's empty the target is reached
范围交叉点基本上我们在该范围内采用块，它是空目标的
for everything around that, we do recovery range.
对于周围的一切，我们进行恢复范围。
For example, we want it to be very optimized.
例如，我们希望它非常优化。
In this way it's very CPU intensive because it's done recovery.
这样，它非常密集，因为它已经完成了恢复。
We spawn multiple Tokyo task that does everything in the parallel.
我们催生了多个Tokyo任务，该任务可以在并行完成所有操作。
Fetch the transaction that we need if it's in static file.
如果在静态文件中获取我们需要的交易。
And after that, if everything is okay, report the problems.
在那之后，如果一切正常，请报告问题。
If it's not, we update the database table that has that intersection centers.
如果不是这样，我们会更新具有相交中心的数据库表。
The idea for this example is to show that every stage does one thing.
此示例的想法是表明每个阶段都在做一件事。
and every stage can optimize its parameters
每个阶段都可以优化其参数
on the stuff that needs to be done.
关于需要完成的工作。
Instead of recovery, it's CPU-intensive,
它没有恢复，而是CPU密集型，
so we use a lot of Tokyo tasks to parallelize that
因此，我们使用许多东京任务并行化
and we want it to be as, yeah,
我们希望它是，是的，
we can optimize that a lot nicer.
我们可以更好地优化它。
Execution stage is one of the biggest fun and basically takes the longest time to execute.
执行阶段是最大的乐趣之一，基本上花费了最长的执行时间。
The reason for that is basically EVM it's CPU intensive and it's to execute two billion
原因基本上是EVM，它是CPU密集的，是执行200亿
transactions it gets input table from headers canonical header terminal difficulty basically
交易它从标头的输入表典型的标题终端难度基本上难度
all headers and blocks intersection it have it access plain account state and plain storage
所有标题和障碍交叉口都使其访问普通帐户状态和普通存储
and by quotes by quotes are in separate table and updates basically are plain state and account
用引号用引号在单独的表中，基本更新是普通状态和帐户
change sets um yeah unbind it it basically unbinds the changes that it happened on the plain state
更改集um是的
and change sets got discarded.
变更集被丢弃了。
Yeah.
是的。
Hashing storage.
哈希存储。
I'm not sure if there is questions around this
我不确定是否有问题
or should I go over to the database?
还是我应该转到数据库？
um there's not any maybe specific questions around what you're talking about now but
嗯，您现在在说什么，但没有任何具体问题
there's some requests for um maybe you to go through the process of building a block
有一些要求UM的要求，也许您要经历建立块的过程
and using the state transits and function in wrath maybe that fits here maybe it fits
并在愤怒中使用状态转移和功能也许适合这里
later on in the presentation uh how to build the block
稍后在演示文稿中如何构建块
Okay, I will come to the payload builder.
好吧，我会来到有效载荷构建器。
Cool.
凉爽的。
Okay, yes.
好的，是的。
Um, yeah, storage is interesting one.
嗯，是的，存储很有趣。
In storage, we have a codex that does,
在存储中，我们有一个法典，可以
for the keys it needs to be encoded,
对于钥匙，它需要编码，
while for the values it needs to be compressed.
对于值，它需要被压缩。
We still need to have that,
我们仍然需要
we cannot compress integer and lose
我们不能压缩整数和输
the greater than ability.
大于能力。
Compact, this is for compression.
紧凑，这是用于压缩的。
For database,
对于数据库，
Static files, yeah.
静态文件，是的。
We have abstraction that allows us to abstractivate the database currently we just have mdbx but
我们的抽象使我们能够抽象化数据库当前我们只有MDBX，但是
the idea was to replace it or have ability to switch the databases.
这个想法是替换它或具有切换数据库的能力。
yeah this implement this trace-based abstraction over very low-level database access where
是的，这在非常低级的数据库访问中实现了此基于跟踪的抽象
you have the section mutable to section that gives you right access cursor is interesting
您的部分可与部分相变，使您正确的访问光标很有趣
one that allows you to iterate over the the values or in the database this can be very
一个允许您迭代值或数据库中的一个可以非常
faster way to fetch intersections or block or calculate the Merkle route when it's needed
更快地获取相交或阻止或计算默克尔路线时的方法
because accessing the values one after another is a lot faster than randomly seeking the
因为一个接一个地访问值的速度比随机寻求的速度要快得多
values.
值。
This is true for the writes.
写作是正确的。
So if you want to write an amount of data it's a lot faster if you can sort them and
因此，如果您想编写大量数据，如果可以对它们进行排序，并且
write it in sorted order.
以排序顺序写入。
DB basically is the low-level key-value database it implements.
DB基本上是IT实施的低级键值数据库。
are most interesting here basically the data layout that we have inside the red table view
在这里，最有趣的是，我们在红色表视图中拥有的数据布局
ah here they are
啊，他们是
um canonical headers allows us key to block number to the header hash
um规范的标题允许我们钥匙阻止数字到标题哈希
timer difficulties used for the
计时器困难用于
for the proof of work currently not used here the numbers this is utility block hash to the block
对于目前未使用的工作证明，此数字是实用程序块哈希
number headers this is the table that uh have headers indexed by the block number block body
编号标头这是uh的表格，该桌子由块号块主体索引
indices we have what's interesting here we have transactions that are indexed by transaction
索引我们有有趣的事务，这些交易是由交易索引的
number to the section and block body indices is basically telling us for this block number
该部分的数字和块主索引基本上告诉我们此块号
uh amount of uh what the section number basically falls into this block
uh量的uh截面号基本上落入了这个块
block uh block commerce uh
阻止UH Block Commerce UH
block withdrawals this is for the proof of stake this for the side blocks that got included
块提取这是为了证明这一点的证明
almost basically
几乎基本上
um everything is table this table is like indexed by the ordinary intersection number
嗯，一切都是表
That's basically number of the section and number of the section that got executed.
这基本上是执行的部分和截面的编号。
It's a lot easier to fetch one transaction if needed.
如果需要，进行一次交易要容易得多。
The section hash number is inverse.
哈希号的部分是逆的。
If you want to fetch the section by the hash, we get the transaction number.
如果要通过哈希获取部分，我们会得到交易号。
This index it stores the highest
该索引存储最高
to the section number of this block.
到此块的截面号。
Basically it's not every intersection number to the block
基本上，这并不是块的每个交集号码
it's the highest just.
这是最高的公正。
This allows us to from the section number
这使我们可以从截面号
to fetch the block number.
获取块号。
Receipts are indexed by the section number,
收据由部分编号索引，
byte code indexed by it's hash.
字节代码由其哈希索引。
This is the plain state.
这是普通状态。
basically execution stage updates the plain state the play state has just for the play account
基本上是执行阶段更新平原状态，播放状态仅适用于Play帐户
play state it has address and just account information account information just this
播放状态它具有地址，只有帐户信息帐户信息
balance and all while the storage has keys basically account subkey or in this
余额，所有在存储中都有钥匙基本帐户子键或
yes, subkey is hash, basically, key of that storage.
是的，subkey是哈希，基本上是该存储的关键。
Because I mentioned subkeys, mdbx allows to have duplicate values inside tables.
因为我提到了子键，所以MDBX允许在表中具有重复的值。
This allows us to have a little bit faster access to some values.
这使我们可以更快地访问某些值。
In this case, we can have main key address and subkey basically to be hash.
在这种情况下，我们可以拥有主要的关键地址，并且基本上可以放大。
Account history is interesting, but first I want to talk about change sets.
帐户历史记录很有趣，但首先我想谈谈变更集。
Account change sets, storage change sets for every block number, we have account before
帐户更改集，每个块号的存储更改集，我们之前有帐户
The section and subkey of that is address.
该部分和子键是地址。
So for every block, for every change account,
因此，对于每个块，对于每个变更帐户，
we have it's previous values.
我们有以前的值。
Change set for the table, for every block number
为表的更改设置，每个块号
and address for address is account.
地址的地址为帐户。
We have storage key and previous storage value.
我们有存储密钥和先前的存储值。
These change sets are generated by the execution
这些更改集由执行生成
and used by the Merkle tree to,
并由默克尔树使用
or any history tracing for RPC if you need.
或任何历史记录跟踪RPC（如果需要）。
Format tree is used for the incremental
格式树用于增量
Merkle tree calculation,
默克树计算，
because when you calculate our first Merkle tree,
因为当您计算我们的第一个默克尔树时，
all the documentation, all the calculation
所有文档，所有计算
of the Merkle tree should be incremental.
默克尔树的含量应为增量。
And, after we have those change sets, we are doing account history, basically, for every,
而且，在我们进行了这些更改集之后，我们基本上都在做帐户历史记录
in this case, sharded key, for every address, and basically it contains for every account,
在这种情况下，对于每个地址，碎片密钥，基本上都包含每个帐户，
it contains list of blocks where that account got changed.
它包含更改该帐户的块列表。
So if you want to find block
因此，如果您想找到块
account balance of the block 1 million
100万块的帐户余额
we are checking the
我们正在检查
where that account got changed next.
下一个帐户在哪里更改。
If this change is 1 million 1 block
如果此更改是100万个块
then we need to fetch the change set
然后我们需要获取更改集
of that account so history account history and storage history as loves allows us to
在该帐户中，历史帐户历史和存储历史记录允许我们
index the change set and find the change that happened in the history
索引更改集并找到历史中发生的变化
uh hashed account here storage
uh Hashed帐户在这里存储
uh are used by the market tree basically they need to have for the first calculation
嗯，市场树使用了基本上需要进行第一次计算
mca3 they need to have sorted hashed accounts
他们需要对哈希帐户进行分类
days there was idea
天有主意
to basically merge hashed accounts and plain accounts plain basically state with hashtag
基本上合并了Hashed帐户和普通帐户，基本上是与主题标签
state so that we only have hash state it will reduce the footprint in database for around
说明我们只有哈希州状态，它将减少数据库中的占地面积
100 gigabytes it shouldn't matter a lot for performance you need still if you want to
100千兆字节，如果您愿意
fetch account you still need to get you need to hash it but but for our measurements for
获取帐户，您仍然需要获得您需要进行哈希的帐户，但是为了我们的测量
So it leaves historical sync, main bottleneck execution sync is EVM.
因此，它留下了历史同步，主瓶颈执行同步是EVM。
So it would matter a lot.
所以这很重要。
Account tree, storage tree are Merkle, Patricia, basically the nodes that are needed for calculation
帐户树，存储树是默克尔，帕特里夏，基本上是计算所需的节点
it allows it to fetch the address it's used in execution and it's needed for the sender recovery
它允许它获取执行中使用的地址，并且发件人恢复所需
stage checkpoints allows us to know where the stage where the stage stopped and what we need
舞台检查点使我们能够知道舞台停止的位置以及我们需要什么
to do next. Prune checkpoints allows us to know until when we pruned our data. Basically, pruning,
接下来做。修剪检查点，直到我们修剪数据时，才能知道。基本上，修剪，
there are multiple parameters that can be set, but pruning mostly means that we remove
可以设置多个参数，但是修剪主要意味着我们删除
change sets and indexes of those change sets. So it removes history data, so only the
这些更改集的更改集和索引。因此它删除了历史数据，因此只有
the tip can be fetched.
尖端可以被提取。
And the last table is, of course, history.
当然，最后一个桌子是历史。
Do you have questions around this?
您对此有疑问吗？
Or was this too much?
还是太多了？
Can you share?
你可以分享吗？
No, no specific questions around that currently.
不，目前没有特定的问题。
Okay, cool.
好吧，很酷。
Yeah, I guess going back to talking about
是的，我想回到谈论
checking verifications, this is kind of back a ways ago,
检查验证，这是一个前面的方法，
but do you, what sort of like drawbacks does not doing
但是你，什么样的缺点不做什么
the Merkle verification checks for every block have?
每个块都有默克尔验证检查吗？
Drawbacks are basically, we don't have proof of the history.
基本上是缺点，我们没有历史的证据。
The get and open Ethereum basically had, you could at every point of time fetch the basically
基本上，以太坊的获取和打开的以太坊都可以在每个时间点基本上获取
Merkle proof of every storage of account.
每个帐户存储的默克尔证明。
This is removed.
这将被删除。
we only have a market proof of one point of in one point of time
我们只有一个时间点的市场证明
so we need to like um be aware when we do reorg at the tip to unbind market tree and update
因此，我们需要喜欢UM注意何时在小费上进行reorg，以解开市场树并更新
market maybe one drawback could be uh increased complexity but in general market tree and everything
市场也许一个缺点可能是增加复杂性，但在一般的市场树和一切
it's very complex because it's like in the end you get what just one hash and
这很复杂，因为最终您会得到一个哈希和
every verification depends on that cache it doesn't mean it does you don't have like
每个验证都取决于该缓存，这并不意味着您不喜欢
intermediate steps how to get that where where is the step that you made mistake or not but yeah
中级步骤如何获得您犯错的步骤，无论是否在哪里
right
正确的
you asked about yeah
你问的是
about verification.
关于验证。
What kind of verification?
什么样的验证？
Block verification or?
块验证还是？
Yes.
是的。
So Matt was explaining the get code base
所以马特正在解释获取代码基础
from the perspective of state transition function.
从状态过渡函数的角度来看。
So basically creating a new block by verifying transaction
因此，基本上通过验证交易来创建新块
and including them into a block, calculating the header.
并将它们包括在一个块中，计算标头。
And, like, in reality this happens when you're asked to build a blog, but generally it's
而且，就像，实际上，当您被要求建立博客时，这会发生，但通常是
like the verification in GET, and of course it's different in RED, but if you could maybe
就像GET的验证一样，当然在红色上有所不同，但是如果您可以
guide us through the code base where this happens, where the, also like, some, like,
引导我们通过发生这种情况的代码库，在某些情况下，有些（例如）
um uh where the evm pre-compiles are uh which is which is specific to red and um yeah yeah there's
嗯，嗯，evm预编译为uh，这是红色和嗯，是的，是的
three places where where we are executed to section one is inside the pipeline
我们被执行到第一节的三个地方在管道内
this is inside the stage all them are similar but a little bit different
这是在舞台内部的，它们都相似，但有点不同
and most different half the handle output of the data.
大多数不同的一半是数据的手柄输出。
Where it is, metrics, stages, source.
它在哪里，指标，阶段，来源。
A lot of checks on the block and the sectional error
块上的大量检查和分段错误
are encapsulated inside REVM.
被封装在REVM中。
So a lot of heavy lifting is done by REVM.
因此，REVM完成了很多繁重的工作。
Example here, start block here in the stages,
示例在这里，在此处启动块，
We iterate our start block to the max block, depending on the range of the blocks that
根据块的范围，我们将起始块迭代到最大块
we want to execute.
我们想执行。
We fetch headers, we fetch senders of that block, and here we execute the verify receipts.
我们获取标题，我们获取该块的发件人，在这里我们执行验证收据。
Basically here we have a block and we have total difficulty that's needed for the proof
基本上，我们有一个障碍，我们有一个完全的困难来证明
work basically history execution and this is the yeah we have one to
工作基本上是历史执行，这是我们有一个
encapsulate different basically it's called processors for example to have
基本上封装不同的不同，它称为处理器
optimist processor than to care minute or processor and to have ability to
乐观主义者处理器比关心分钟或处理器，并具有
switch them when needed. For example, this is the main net. Yeah, the main processor
在需要时切换它们。例如，这是主要网络。是的，主处理器
that we have. In here it executes inner block it initialized basically array VM with it
我们有。在此处，它执行内部块，它基本上是与之初始化的数组VM
header it initialize applies uh beacon root contract call basically there is system call
标题IT初始化应用UH信标根合同呼叫基本上是系统调用
that's done on the with cancun that updates um consensus layer hash block hash and here
这是在更新UM共识层哈希块哈希和此处更新的cancun上完成的
Here we execute transactions.
在这里，我们执行交易。
Basically this everything is done in processor.
基本上，这一切都是在处理器中完成的。
In for every block we take transaction, basically this iterator, check the gas limit for that
在每个块中，我们进行交易，基本上是此迭代器，检查该迭代器的气体限制
block and transect.
块和样带。
This is function of REVM.
这是REVM的功能。
oh we are still here
哦，我们还在这里
yeah
是的
we filled the
我们填补了
resection parameters
切除参数
check if we need
检查我们是否需要
to call
打电话
tracer
示踪剂
that we are calling
我们正在打电话
it inspector
IT检查员
with REVM
与Revm
we basically
我们基本上
need to
需要
add
添加
handlers
处理者
for that
为此
tracing
跟踪
and here
在这里
and here we do
我们在这里做
resect
切除
Trasect in general, we are now in REVM it validates the data that we receive from the
总体而言，我们现在正在REVM中，它验证了我们从
RET it checks initial transaction gas if we are okay it checks the transaction against
ret检查将检查初始交易气
the state so here we until here we just check the data that we receive here fetch the account
状态因此，我们在这里直到这里我们只检查了我们在此处收到的数据获取帐户
that's of a intersection, of the center of the intersection.
那是交叉路口的交叉点。
And we start execution.
我们开始执行。
Yeah, we are now in REVM still. It was recently refactored,
是的，我们现在仍在REVM中。最近被重构了，
So we have separation of the context and the logic.
因此，我们将上下文和逻辑分开。
Context is the data, transactions, block, and pre-compiles,
上下文是数据，交易，阻止和预编译，
but the logic is handled inside the handlers,
但是逻辑是在处理程序内部处理的，
how it's called?
怎么称呼？
Here, context and handlers.
在这里，上下文和处理者。
A handler contains the list of the functions
处理程序包含功能列表
that contain logic.
包含逻辑。
So you can do anything around it.
因此，您可以围绕它做任何事情。
The idea is in the future to be able, it's used even now, to register new handlers that
这个想法是将来能够使用的，即使现在已经使用了
will allow you like optimist level changes or optimist logic to be implemented inside
将允许您喜欢乐观级别的更改或乐观主义逻辑
REVM.
REVM。
Something similar it's done on the scope of the RET, but it's a little bit nicer now.
它在RET的范围上完成了类似的操作，但是现在好多了。
still need to do some refactoring in revm
仍然需要在REVM中进行一些重构
um it is transect
嗯，它是样带
here we are the first step first handler is loading accounts
在这里，我们是第一步，第一处理程序是加载帐户
after that is loading pre-copiles for example you can have handler that
之后正在加载前围栏，例如，您可以使用处理程序
loads additional pre-copiles
加载额外的预媒体
We now deduct the caller with the maximum gas limit that it can potentially use.
现在，我们以可能使用的最大气体限制来扣除呼叫者。
Idea is so that while the section is in the process, he cannot send more balance than he has.
想法是这样的，在该部分正在进行过程中，他无法提供比他更多的平衡。
a calculated gas limit depending on the set gas limit inside the section and deducting the initial
计算出的气体限制，具体取决于部分内部的气体限制并扣除初始气体限制
gas spend that's depending on the how much zeros and ones do you have and what type of the section
汽油支出取决于您拥有多少零和零体
and everything on that here we execute it there is at least two types of execution
在这里，我们执行它至少有两种类型的执行
it broadly called to contract and creating new contract when this is finished we have
它广泛要求合同并在完成后建立新合同，我们有
here's the main loop um a few months ago we had like recursion call between the sub calls when
这是几个月前的主要循环
the contract called on the additional contract this is now changed to just simple loop
召集的额外合同合同现在已更改为简单的循环
it's run the loop, the main loop of the EVM, here it's done, where it just loops over the
它正在运行循环，即EVM的主要循环，在这里完成，它只是循环
stack frames, and stack frame is for example, band call or sub call, sub call, sub call,
堆栈框架和堆栈帧例如，频段呼叫或sub呼叫，sub call，sub call，
charts interpreter that checks the bytecode and executes it instructions let's go back
图表解释器检查字节码并执行IT指令，让我们回去
after execution is finished
执行完成后
we take
我们接受
we have some uh basically we need to handle when the last frame of the execution last color create
我们有一些UH基本上需要处理最后一个颜色的最后框架创建的最后框架
returns we need to handle some logic there after that we reimburse caller with the gas that's not
回报我们需要在那里处理一些逻辑之后，我们用不属于的气体向呼叫者报销呼叫者
spent we reward beneficiary that's basically sending minor reward uh minor reward is sent
花费的我们奖励受益人基本上发送较小的奖励uh un tir奖励。
for the proof of work while this is yeah it's sent for the board proof of stake and pro for
为了工作证明，这是的，它已发送给董事会证明和专业证明
and we handle output here that returns error if it happened or returns the byte code the
我们在这里处理输出，如果发生错误或返回字节代码，则返回错误
bytes that got returned yeah yeah that's mostly it from the revm
返回的字节是的，是的，主要是从revm那里
Now we are inside the RET, still in the processor, execute the section.
现在，我们仍在RET内，仍在处理器中，执行该部分。
When the section gets executed, we get some result outside of it.
当该部分执行后，我们将获得一些结果。
We check how much time elapsed and we commit that state inside our database.
我们检查了多少时间，并在数据库内提交该状态。
So REVM it basically doesn't commit anything if you don't want it.
因此，如果您不想要它，它基本上不会提交任何内容。
That it basically returns the state that got changed.
它基本上返回了变更的状态。
After that, we communicate GAS, create receipt, and that's it.
之后，我们传达气体，创建收据，仅此而已。
If you go back, execute inner, we check if the gas matches the gas used, and we check
如果您返回，执行内部，我们检查气体是否与使用的气体相匹配，并检查
if the...
如果...
Now, we have post-execution state change that is minor reward that was before in the proof
现在，我们有执行后状态变化，这是前面的较小奖励
of work.
工作。
We check, do we need to prune data or not, basically not merge it or not.
我们检查，我们是否需要修剪数据，基本上不合并它。
Merge the section.
合并部分。
And receipts, return receipts.
和收据，退货收据。
And here, we verify our receipts, save receipts if they are okay.
在这里，我们验证收据，如果可以的话，请保存收据。
So both the stages use execute and verify receipts while the block builder uses just
因此，两个阶段都使用执行和验证收据，而块构建器仅使用
execute, so it doesn't need to verify receipts while the execution is happening.
执行，因此在执行时不需要验证收据。
This is in the stage.
这是在舞台上。
Stage is one place where REVM is used.
阶段是使用REVM的一个地方。
Second place is inside the blockchain tree.
第二位是区块链树内。
blockchain tree.
区块链树。
Event, state, block, canonical chain.
事件，状态，街区，规范链。
This is for the blockchain tree, everything is done in the memory.
这是针对区块链树，一切都在内存中完成。
So you have some pending state it's used wrap inside wrap around the database chain it's
因此，您有一些等待的状态，它已在数据库链周围包装中使用了包裹
it's not extend canonical chain it's not that it is bundle state no shareable fork
这不是扩展的规范链，不是因为它是捆绑状态没有可共享的叉子
it's not insert but
不是插入，而是
fork forgot how it's called trying to set it to sidebar here it is
叉忘了如何将其设置为侧边栏是如何在这里
parent shade where we append the block to the chain that is currently inside
父母的阴影，我们将块附加到当前内部的链条
the it's inside the chain
它在链中
Here we called ValidAtTheExecute.
在这里，我们称为palifattheexecute。
ValidAtTheExecute, we need now to have like the view on the database that you want to
validatTheexecute，我们现在需要像您想要的数据库上一样
execute on, plus the padding state that we have inside the blockchain tree.
执行，加上我们在区块链树内的填充状态。
and we wrap that inside some database straight and we call here we create executor
我们将其包装在某些数据库中，然后在这里打电话给我们创建执行程序
block execution execute verify receipt we all been there
块执行执行验证收据我们都去过那里
yeah basically it use the processor again to verify everything to verify to execute everything
是的，基本上它再次使用处理器来验证所有内容以验证以执行所有内容
because both the blockchain tree and the stages need it to have all the data it need to just
因为区块链树和阶段都需要它拥有所有需要的数据
verify if they are correct or not
验证他们是否正确
and the third place is inside the nodes
第三位在节点内
payloads ethereum
有效载荷以太坊
We have multiple builders for Optimize for Ethereum because it's a little bit different.
我们有多个建筑商可以优化以太坊，因为它有些不同。
I think that's it.
我认为就是这样。
Default Ethereum payload builder.
默认以太坊有效载荷构建器。
We create the database, we create payload what's needed, pre-block beacon route contract
我们创建数据库，创建有效载荷所需的内容，预块信标路由合同
call, basically this is the system call enabled inside Cancun.
呼叫，基本上，这是在坎昆内启用的系统调用。
We get the section for the section pool here, check if we have cumulative gas used more
我们在此处获取部分池的部分，检查是否有更多的气体使用
than the set gas limit of the block that you want to build.
比您要构建的块的设定气体限制。
Is AIP, if it is blob, here we create just our EVM
是AIP，如果是斑点，我们只是创建我们的EVM
and we use our EVM to transect.
我们使用EVM进行横切。
It doesn't go through the processor.
它不会通过处理器。
It uses EVM directly.
它直接使用EVM。
if it is error
如果是错误
that means the same validation
这意味着相同的验证
or some checks are not
或一些检查不是
correct
正确的
if it is ok then
如果可以的话
that state gets
那个状态得到
committed to the database
致力于数据库
and this is done
这是完成的
until
直到
until we have
直到我们有
until we have enough gas
直到我们有足够的气体
to fill the block
填充块
yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes,
是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，
yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes,
是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是，是否，是，是，是，是，是，是，
need for the header, state root, calculate the section root, here we calculate the section
需要标头状态根，计算截面根，在这里我们计算截面
basically root, here we should calculate, yeah, that's mostly it.
基本上是扎根，在这里我们应该计算，是的，主要是这样。
Is there any questions around this?
这有什么问题吗？
I'm not sure if I killed listeners.
我不确定我是否杀了听众。
We're still here with you.
我们仍然和你在一起。
And there were some questions.
还有一些问题。
I'm not sure if blog-building-related.
我不确定与博客构建有关。
Yeah, there was a question following up on the one
是的，有一个问题跟随一个
that we discussed before on skipping
我们在跳过之前讨论了
the Merkle verification.
默克尔验证。
So whether this also applies to storage balances,
因此，这是否也适用于存储余额，
How do we get accurate accounts for a particular block when you don't calculate the Merkle?
当您不计算默克尔时，我们如何获得特定块的准确帐户？
So it's basically...
所以基本上是...
Yeah.
是的。
I'm not sure if I understood it.
我不确定我是否理解。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
the Merkle optimization, whether it is compared to other clients, whether there is a difference
Merkle优化，是否与其他客户进行比较，是否存在差异
how you get those basically intermediate states and all the data for particular block when
当您如何获得这些基本中间状态和特定块的所有数据
you don't get it from calculating it from the Merkle data.
您不会从Merkle数据中计算它来获得它。
uh for the blob we for the blobs or accounts for the blob we don't have anything that's mostly
呃，为斑点我们为斑点或blob的帐户，我们没有任何东西
on there but in general yeah uh we check assumption is basically that we can make is
在那里，但总的来说，我们检查的假设基本上是我们可以做出的
for the history block that are blocked for the finalize we need to check it only once
对于最终确定的历史记录块，我们只需要检查一次
we don't need to check every previous state because if you check just the present state
我们不需要检查以前的每个状态，因为如果您仅检查当前状态
or present state in the tip, we know that we have correct state. After that, we just incrementally
或提示中的当前状态，我们知道我们有正确的状态。之后，我们只是逐步
check Merkle state, Merkle-like root, and it's a lot faster algorithm.
检查Merkle状态，类似Merkle的根，并且算法更快。
yeah can you
是的，你可以吗
another question here is
这里的另一个问题是
what is the sender recovery
发件人恢复是什么
in execution stage
在执行阶段
basically when the section is sent
基本上是发送部分时
you only have like the
你只有
the payload and you
有效载荷和你
have signature
有签名
from the signature you are recovering
从您正在恢复的签名中
the sender basically who is
发件人基本上是谁
the guy or girl
男孩或女孩
who sent that section
谁发送了该部分
So that can be very CPU-intensive, and that's why we have separate stage for it.
因此，这可能是非常密集的，这就是为什么我们有单独的阶段。
We will save that value inside the database so it's it's faster to fetch it from the database
我们将在数据库中保存该值，因此从数据库中获取它的速度更快
than to recalculate it again inside the SQL stage.
而不是在SQL阶段再次重新计算它。
Okay, and we were discussing the database engine mdbx.
好的，我们正在讨论数据库引擎MDBX。
Maybe if you can tell a bit about that, like what are the main differences with leveldb or pebble?
也许如果您可以告诉一下，例如LevelDB或Cebble的主要区别是什么？
that is mostly mdbx uh basically we
这主要是mdbx uh，我们基本上是
shrink the scope or how we use it static files for the intersections and blocks and receipts are
缩小范围或我们如何使用IT静态文件作为交叉点，块和收据
profiti fine basically binary files saying like open the file put the section some indexing
利润罚款基本上是二进制文件，说像打开文件一样，将部分放置一些索引
it works very nice for mdbx it allows it to have like
它对MDBX的工作非常好，它允许它喜欢
atomic-like, atomic-like, like fetches from the hard disk level.
像原子一样，像原子一样，就像从硬盘级别获取。
So it allows you to have ability to open new process and read the database in read-only
因此，它允许您具有打开新过程并阅读数据库的能力
mode.
模式。
That's one of the use cases.
那是用例之一。
It is bit-tree-like database it's faster on the reads, so it's more useful for the execution.
它是类似于位的数据库的读取速度，因此对执行更有用。
So yeah, we are investigating replacement for it.
是的，我们正在调查替代品。
I don't think it's something that we are going to stay long-term.
我认为这不会长期保持。
But for now it's working and it's basically doing the job it needs to do.
但是就目前而言，它正在工作，基本上是在完成需要做的工作。
So we are open for new alternatives, but for now, yeah.
因此，我们愿意寻求新的替代方案，但是现在，是的。
Yeah, interesting.
是的，很有趣。
Yeah, Virginia documentation in Russian, right?
是的，弗吉尼亚州的俄罗斯文档，对吗？
Yeah.
是的。
We have a English one as well.
我们也有一个英语。
Okay.
好的。
I don't see any more new questions.
我看不到任何新问题。
Oh, yeah, there was, whether you could point us,
哦，是的，有，您是否可以指出我们，
yeah, we have, like, last 10 minutes.
是的，我们有最后10分钟。
Maybe if you could show us the Engine API communication
也许如果您可以向我们展示引擎API通信
and how this block building is triggered by new payload,
以及如何通过新有效载荷触发该块建筑物，
like, or where does this happen?
像，还是在哪里发生？
Okay.
好的。
The ng-api is a bit hidden because it's it is inside consensus so it's crates consensus
NG-API有点隐藏，因为它是内部共识，所以它是板条
beacon engine.
信标发动机。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
block client listeners hooks yeah be cool consider sentient here it is this
block客户听众挂钩是的，很酷，考虑到这是有意识的
may structure that has a blockchain tree that has ngc controller controls the
可能结构有一个具有NGC控制器的区块链树控制
pipeline um and a lot of basically it is quite complex because it needs to hit synchronize a lot
管道嗯，基本上很复杂，因为它需要击中同步很多
of components from payload builder to the focus update to the blockchain tree to the pipeline
从有效载荷构建器到焦点更新到区块链树到管道的组件
and it's like control hub of everything around it it is implemented as the feature
就像它周围所有事物的控制枢纽一样，它被实现为功能
Here it is.
这里是。
Fork choice update.
叉选择更新。
On fork choice update.
关于叉选择更新。
It should be in that kind.
它应该是那种。
Consistent state, ensure canonical update head.
一致的状态，确保规范更新头。
Process payload attributes.
流程有效载荷属性。
Yep, here it is.
是的，是。
There's RPC part that calls this work trace update,
RPC部分称此工作跟踪更新，
but I think this main entry point,
但是我认为这个主要切入点，
work with latest should be at her
最新工作应该在她身上
Basically in here, we check if the pipeline is active.
基本上，在这里，我们检查管道是否处于活动状态。
If it's active, we are not receiving.
如果它活跃，我们将不会收到。
We are in the syncing process.
我们处于同步过程中。
We check if we have right hook on the database.
我们检查数据库上是否有正确的挂钩。
That's more.
更多。
Here, make canonical.
在这里，制作规范。
We tell the blockchain tree to make this block that we received.
我们告诉区块链树以使我们收到的块。
as canonical because fortress update has just the hash and if this has some problems or there is some
如规范性，因为要塞更新只有哈希，并且如果有一些问题或有一些问题
i don't know uh state truth is not calculated correctly or something like that we need to go
我不知道状态真理不是正确计算的，或者我们需要去的类似事项
to like arrow handling or fail canonical fortress update or if it's okay we need to check outcome
喜欢箭头处理或失败的规范堡垒更新，或者如果可以的话，我们需要查看结果
if it is all decanonical
如果都是decan的
because it can possible
因为可能
it is possible to have
有可能拥有
multiple consensus layer
多个共识层
basically connected to one execution layer
基本上连接到一个执行层
so maybe they are sending
所以也许他们正在发送
the same Fuck Choice update
同样的他妈的选择更新
if it is
如果是
all decanonical, if it is committed
全部decan讽，如果承诺
that means that it is
这意味着它是
sent to the database
发送到数据库
and
和
yeah, ensure consistent state
是的，确保状态一致
yeah in general there is a lot of things happening here
是的，总的来说，这里发生了很多事情
on fork choice update
关于叉选择更新
where is the main
主要在哪里
oh here it is ah this is the main pool yeah win plan future
哦，这里是啊，这是主要池是赢得计划的未来
it is the loop over the bcox-sysengine that acts like it pulls everything that actions
BCOX-SYSENGINE上的循环表现得像是拉动所有动作的一切
that need to happen.
那需要发生。
One of them is Fuck Choice Update, one of them is Process Sync Event, and I think here
其中之一是他妈的选择更新，其中之一是过程同步活动，我认为在这里
it will have to finalize on Hook Result.
它将必须在钩结果上完成。
Yeah, here it is, here, yeah.
是的，在这里，是的。
If it is a forked choice update, if it is a new payload that it received from the consensus
如果是分叉的选择更新，如果它是从共识中获得的新有效载荷
layer, if it is a new event that needs to be happening, it's configuration.
层，如果这是需要发生的新事件，则是配置。
I'm not sure even what's that.
我不确定那是什么。
Maybe I'm not the best person to explore this.
也许我不是探索这个问题的最佳人选。
But yeah, if you want to dive deeper it's in Cosensus beacon engine it handles basically
但是，是的，如果您想更深入研究它，它基本上可以处理在Cosensus Beacon引擎中
uh
嗯
synchronization between the pipeline
管道之间的同步
blockchain tree builder and
区块链树木建造者和
everything around it even the
周围的一切
pruner
修剪
sorry that I don't
对不起，我没有
have yeah yeah that's
是的，那是
right it's all good um
是的，一切都很好
Thank you very much. We had a question about the tree parallel trait.
非常感谢。我们对树的平行特征有疑问。
Whether you can give us just an overview, we have last few minutes, of the tree-parallel.
无论您是否只能给我们一个概述，我们有最后几分钟的树平行。
What we noticed, we had argument that implemented tree-parallel.
我们注意到的是，我们的论点实现了树平行。
basically we have tree and tree parallel.
基本上，我们有树和树平行。
They do the same thing, but in different ways.
他们做同样的事情，但是以不同的方式做。
We have very like optimized way to calculate
我们非常喜欢优化的计算方法
mclroute from the plain state,
来自平原状态的mclroute，
from the basically after we finished the pipeline.
从根本上讲，我们完成了管道。
But what we noticed that same calculation
但是我们注意到相同的计算
was not good enough for the tip,
对小费还不够好
Because for the tip, basically, we need the better way to do it is to do it calculation
因为对于小费，基本上，我们需要更好的方法是进行计算
in the parallel.
在平行中。
I don't know exactly the algorithm it's not the thing that I worked on.
我不知道算法并不是我从事的事情。
So it's very new.
所以这是非常新的。
idea is to I think just make it in parallel
想法是我认为只有并行
yeah don't have a lot to say here to be honest
是的，说实话没有太多要说的
it's all right thank you so much yeah uh just uh just a quick quick overview
没关系，非常感谢，是的，嗯，只是快速概述
yes any other personal code you guys would like to ask about maybe it would
是的，你们想问的其他任何个人代码也许会问
ask something more general maybe and a bit further from the red itself because
问一些更一般的东西，也许与红色本身有点远，因为
there are many people you know trying to contribute up learning rest up I'm
我认识很多人试图做出贡献的学习休息我
wondering but we have any any suggestions any recommendations advice
想知道，但我们有任何建议
for people getting into Rust and learning this unforgivable language?
对于生锈的人们并学习这种不可原谅的语言？
If you start in Rust, the book is the main resource.
如果您从Rust开始，那么这本书是主要资源。
Basically it's official documentation it's very nice, I think every Rust developer started
基本上是官方文档，非常好，我认为每个生锈开发人员都开始
from there it's that good.
从那里很好。
you only know rust and want to contribute good uh labels it work on uh good first
您只知道Rust，并想为它贡献良好的标签。
uh there are a lot of them good first
嗯，有很多很好
uh is it is it dash or yeah yeah yeah good first issue there is a lot of like small tasks that can
嗯，是破折号还是是的，是的，是的，好的第一期，有很多小任务可以
be done move with their scan types to alloy it's like porting and just um
用扫描类型移动到合金上，就像移植一样，只是嗯
matt created for four days ago matt is yes uh does uh uh red already supports the the ots uh
马特（Matt）创建了四天前，马特（Matt
namespace for otter scan yeah we i think yeah to be honest i'm not following a lot i moved myself
Otter Scan的名称空间是的，我们认为是的，老实说，我没有很多事情
to the revm and i have a lot of stuff there but yeah we have water scan i think we have
对于REVM，我在那里有很多东西，但是，是的，我们有水扫描，我认为我们有
water scan support um it's for example there is like phase out eaters dependence replace
水扫描支撑um，例如，逐步的食食者依赖替换
vital provider for example always provider a new rewrite of features
例如，重要提供商始终提供新功能的新重写
replace bite smooth feedback there's a lot of small like tasks that can be done but anybody
替换咬合光滑的反馈
we like joke around it uh there was even a lot one guy that made the script where he scanned
我们喜欢周围的玩笑，嗯，甚至有很多人在他扫描的地方制作了剧本
the issues and if he if he found good first issue he would just grab it and he made like
这些问题以及如果他找到好的第一期，他只会抓住它，然后他像
yes he made the script basically comment in the loop and it was like broken and
是的，他基本上在循环中评论了脚本，就像破碎了
it was trying to snipe the first good issues
它试图狙击第一个好问题
and spammed comments
和垃圾评论
yeah exactly
是的
but either way there's a lot of good first issues
但是无论哪种方式都有很多好的第一个问题
that can be taken
可以采取
yeah awesome
是的，真棒
I'm very excited about this part of Red
我对红色的这一部分感到非常兴奋
being so open to contributors
对贡献者如此开放
especially
尤其
how do you see it from your side as a developer
您如何从您身边看到它
like is it hard as a maintainer to to get so many uh you know questions and just prs which might be
就像一个维护者一样，很难获得这么多你知道问题，只是PRS可能是
low quality or so like how are you having it go with the flow basically
低质量左右，就像您的流量基本上如何相处
me as the basically maintainer uh i need to take care of my time but i want to help people
我是基本上维护的人，我需要照顾我的时间，但我想帮助人们
because you never know i from especially revm i know that my first like user was foundry and
因为您永远都不知道我特别是Revm，所以我知道我的第一个喜欢用户是Foundry和
basically i wanted to support all yeah maybe it's different they're high level users but either way
基本上，我想支持所有的是，也许是不同的是高级用户，但无论哪种方式
you never know when somebody's going to go like you never know what happened in the space
你永远不知道何时会像你一样不知道太空发生了什么
because you never know if you help this guy for a little bit he will stay here for like years
因为您永远不知道您是否会帮助这个家伙一点点，他会在这里呆好几年
or build something on top of it but he had like questions for in gmail hey something is
或在其中建立一些东西，但他在Gmail中喜欢问题
not working and it was like one rust feature like needs to be enabled and it's not working and
不起作用，就像一个生锈功能一样，需要启用，并且它不起作用，并且
he built around like library out rev and everything like that i think the team that
他围绕图书馆构建了Rev，以及像我认为团队一样的一切
was behind foundry and the same thing that's now in direct is amazing and they they take care of
是在Foundry的背后，现在直接出现的同一件事是惊人的，他们照顾了
that basically our telegram group is like very lively and i think there is a lot of responses
基本上，我们的电报小组非常活跃，我认为有很多回应
a lot of questions and you're there to support that's why you have you build community at the end
很多问题，您在那里支持这就是为什么您最终建立社区的原因
yeah awesome um yeah i really appreciate the openness and the community approach
是的，很棒的嗯，我真的很感谢开放性和社区方法
and uh i understand it sometimes might be maybe tough with all the contributors coming in yeah um
嗯，我知道有时可能会因为所有贡献者的进来可能很艰难吗？
We don't have any more questions coming, so I think we can rip up here. But thank you so much,
我们再也没有任何问题了，所以我认为我们可以在这里撕毁。但是非常感谢
Dragan. Yeah, I really appreciate it. It was really great insight. We learned a lot.
德拉曼。是的，我真的很感激。这确实是很棒的见识。我们学到了很多。
Also, I have more to learn about the actual stage sync, because it's really nice to see it in the
另外，我还有更多了解实际阶段同步，因为在
logs, right? Like, I'm doing this stage, executing transactions, doing this stage, doing this. It's
日志，对吗？就像，我正在做这个阶段，执行交易，完成此阶段，这样做。它是
really nice to see how the client progresses, but it's different to actually dive into the code. So
看到客户的进展情况真的很高兴，但是实际潜入代码是不同的。所以
So I really thank you so much, Dragan.
所以我真的很感谢你，德拉丹。
Yeah.
是的。
Thank you for calling me.
谢谢你打电话给我。
We sent you the invite to Discord.
我们将邀请函发送给了您。
Feel free to join.
随时加入。
We have a bunch of people eager to learn there.
我们有一群渴望在那里学习的人。
So if you feel like answering some questions,
因此，如果您想回答一些问题，
you're always welcome.
总是欢迎您。
Cool.
凉爽的。
I'll join it.
我会加入。
For the audience, for the study group folks,
对于观众，对于学习小组的人来说，
will continue the week seven on Wednesday with a research track focused on vertical trees. We will
将在周三继续进行第七周，研究轨道集中在垂直树上。我们将
have three or maybe even four speakers covering the vertical tree topics in one session, so don't
在一个会话中有三个甚至三个扬声器涵盖垂直树主题，所以不要
miss that on Wednesday. Next week we will have Paul from Tecku explaining the consensus layer
错过了星期三。下周，我们将从泰克（Tecku）中解释共识层
client. So after dragons execution part, we will have the
客户。因此，在龙执行部分之后，我们将拥有
consensus as well. Ah, yeah, awesome. Yeah, so really
共识。啊，是的，很棒。是的，真的
appreciate it. We have we have great insights, Dragan, and I
感谢它。我们有很好的见解，Dragan和我
will hope to see you around the study group.
希望在研究小组中见到您。
I'm glad to help. Yeah, thanks so much.
我很高兴提供帮助。是的，非常感谢。
Have a great day. Bye bye.
祝你有美好的一天。再见。
Bye, everyone.
再见，大家。
Thank you.
谢谢。